Bock is hard to listen to you have to
listen to his pieces over and over at
least I do I don't suppose you have to
if your musical genius but because the
goal interpreted them personally
it was easier to take the music apart
and understand in an auditory way what
Bach was trying to do music helps
demonstrate the reality of meaning and
it does that for everyone it does that
for people who are deeply atheistic or
even nihilistic and that's interesting
too because you can take bitterly
dissing they listen to music and they're
overwhelmed by a sense of it's really a
sense of religious meaning they don't
even notice it
except that without it they'd be in
trouble some people who they're low in
openness which is a psychological trait
and they're pretty opaque to what art
represents and so they have a hard time
with it or maybe they need more less
sophisticated art it's too shocking to
them if it's sophisticated and and
profound they can't handle it lots of
people are terrified by art if they like
things they like music they like kitsch
because if it's real it's too much for
them they're terrified of it they'll say
I don't like that it's like there isn't
that they don't like it it's that they
can't handle it they're afraid of it
people are even afraid of color you know
that's why everybody uses beige in their
decorating and creams you know they're
terrified of color so people are
terrified of deep truths and no wonder
so they they wouldn't be deep if they
weren't terrifying when we look at the
world we see objects handleable and
usable objects in motion but that isn't
really what the world is like what the
world is like is a set of interlocking
and interconnected patterns at multiple
levels of resolution from the tiniest to
the largest all playing together in a
patterned and somewhat predictable
manner not completely predictable like
music isn't completely predictable and
so the reason that music is meaningful
when you listen to it is because music
demonstrates to you what the structure
of the universe is actually like and
your senses your visual sense blinds you
to that because it's more practical in a
way it shows you what you need to
right now whereas music gives you this
sculptural picture of quantized patterns
interacting at multiple levels of
analysis simultaneously and that
enthuses people with a sense of meaning
our truly artistic production is full of
inarticulate meaning it's inarticulate
because it's it's it's still in the
developmental stage before articulate
knowledge and so it grips people with a
sense of significance but they can't
necessarily say why and the reason they
can't say why is because the why for
that kind of meaning hasn't been
explicate the reason that art is
meaningful to people is because art is
meaningful
it's full of the next set of ideas
that's one way of looking about it or
it's or it's full of eternal ideas that
people still haven't fully comprehended
and so you can't help but by be gripped
by it